Register of the Vrangel' collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- SHTAB GLAVNOKOMANDUIUSHCHAGO RUSSKOI ARMII, 1918-1924 (Boxes 112-135)
  - (Group I, File 244)
    - Judicial Department (Sudnoe Otdelenie)
      - Case files, contd. (Box 116, Folder 1-2)
        Available on microfilm reel 139
      - Printed matter
        - Pravosudie v voiskakh Generala Vrangelia, Constantinople, 1921 (Folder 3)
        - Proekt "Utverzhdaiu," Pomoshchnik Nachal'nika Bezhenskoi CHasti General'nago SHtaba, "Kratkiia svedeniia nachal'niku eshelona bezhentsev,", August 1921 (Folder 4)
  - (Group I, File 245)
    - Judicial Department (Sudnoe Otdelenie)
      - Case files, Kubanskii Kazachii Korpus, typescript and handwritten material
        - General, criminal cases, Lemnos and Serbia, 1921 (Box 116, Folder 5-6)
        - Fostikov, Lieut.-Gen. Includes "Doznanie Gen. Artifeskova o Gen. Fostikove,", 1921-1923 (Folder 7)
      - Report, "Delo o vostanii na Kubani v iiune-oktiabre 1920g.," handwritten, March 1920 (Folder 8)
  - (Group I, File 246)
    - Judicial Department (Sudnoe Otdelenie)
      - Case files, Bulgaria, typescript and handwritten material, November-December 1922
        - Konstantinopol'skoe Voennoe Uchilishche, "Razsledovanie po delu o sluzhebnykh stolknoveniiakh mezhdu nachal'stvuiushchami litsami K.V.U." (Box 116, Folder 9)
        - "Delo o zloupotrebleniiakh s kazennym imushchestvom..." (Folder 10)
          Available on microfilm reel 140
  - (Group I, File 247)
    - Judicial Department (Sudnoe Otdelenie). Case file, Krymskii (Box 116, Folder 11-12)
    - Kadetskii Korpus, Yugoslavia, handwritten and typescript, 1922-1923
    - Judicial Department (Sudnoe Otdelenie). Case file, Krymskii Kadetskii Korpus, contd. (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - (Group I, File 248)
    - Day-orders of Commander-in-Chief, Baron P. Vrangel', typescript and printed, 1920-1924 (Box 117, Folder 2-3)
    - Printed matter
      - Leaflet, Kirill Vladimirovich, Grand Duke, "Russkii Narod,", August 1922 (Folder 4)
        Available on microfilm reel 141
      - Pamphlets
        - Author unknown
          - Russkaia armiia v izgnanii, 1920-1923 (Folder 5)
          - Svodka svedenii ob armiiakh pogranichnykh s Rossiei gosudarstv, Belgrad, 1924 (Folder 6)
        - A.P., Pravosudie v voiskakh Generala Vrangelia, Constantinople, 1921 (Folder 7)
        - Krimchak, Andra, Pred Jednom Opasnom Probom, Novisad, 1923 (Folder 8)
        - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E., Armiia. Doklad na konferentsii Natsional'nago Soiuza v Parizhe 13 sentiabria 1924 goda, Belgrad (Folder 9)
  - (Group I, File 249)
    - Judicial Department (Sudnoe Otdelenie)
      - List of officers condemned by courts martial and courts of honor, typescript, January 1920-November 1924 (Box 117, Folder 10)
      - Case files, typescript and handwritten material
        - General, October 1922-July 1923 (Folder 11)
        - Donskoi Tekhnicheskii kazachii batalion, May-July 1923 (Folder 12)
        - Fitselaurov, Lieut.-Col., February-April 1923 (Folder 13)
        - Nikolaevskoe Kavaleriiskoe uchilishche, April-August 1923 (Folder 14)
        - Salamakhin and Semenikhin, Cols., June-July, 1922. Includes pamphlets: Skachkov, P., Sredi kazakov otvet na otkrytoe pis'mo gen. P.N. Krasnova k kazakam, Sophia, 1922 and Volia Rossii, No., 16, April 23 1922 (Folder 15)
        - Soiuz Russkikh Invalidov, August 1922-May 1923 and November 1922-April 1923 (Folder 16)
  - (Group I, File 313-352)
    - Otdelenie Dezhurnago Generala: Military Service Records (Posluzhnye Spiski) and Commendation and Promotion Lists (Nagradnye Listy) of officers, medical and other personnel serving in Russian Army. Mostly summaries (Kratkaia Zapiska) of original documents lost during Civil War, typescript and handwritten material, 1917-1924
      - (Group I, File 313)
        - Miscellaneous units, including artillery (Box 118, Folder 1-5)
          Folders 1-2 available on microfilm reel 141; folders 3-5 on reel 142
      - (Group I, File 314)
        - Miscellaneous units (Folder 6-9)
          Available on microfilm reel 142
      - (Group I, File 315)
        - Miscellaneous units (Folder 10-12)
      - (Group I, File 315)
        - Miscellaneous units, contd. (Box 119, Folder 1-4)
          Available on microfilm reel 143
      - (Group I, File 316)
        - General (Folder 5-17)
          Folders 5-15 available on microfilm reel 143; folders 16-17 on reel 144
        - Mai-Maevskii, Maj.-Gen. V. Includes original copy of baptismal record; "Prikaz Voiskam Otriada Generala Mai-Maevskago," printed leaflet; holograph letter from Lieut.-Gen. A. Denikin re appointment of Gen. P. Vrangel' as Commander of Cavalry; military service records, typescript, 1917 and 1918 (Folder 18)
          Available on microfilm reel 144
        - Kutepov, Gen.-of-Infantry Aleksandr P., typescript (?), 1922 (Folder 19)
      - (Group I, File 317)
        - General (Box 120, Folder 1-4)
        - Alekseevskii and Markovskii Pekhotnyi Polk (Folder 5-15)
          Folders 5-13 available on microfilm reel 144; folders 14-15 on reel 145
      - (Group I, File 318)
        - 136-oi Taganrogskii Polk (Folder 16-20)
          Available on microfilm reel 145
        - Svodnyi Gvardeiskii Polk, includes Leib-Gvardii Moskovskii Polk; Leib-Gvardii Keksgol'mskii Polk; Leib-Gvardii Petrogradskii Polk; Leib-Gvardii Vilinskii Polk (Folder 21-24)
      - (Group I, File 318)
        - Svodnyi Gvardeiskii Polk, contd. (Box 121, Folder 1-4)
          Folders 1-2 available on microfilm reel 145; folders 3-4 on reel 146
        - Essen, Fridrikh Fedorovich von, Commander (Folder 5)
          Available on microfilm reel 146
      - (Group I, File 319)
        - Kavaleriiskaia Diviziia, includes officers of Radiotelegrafnoe Otdelenie (I-y Armeiskii Korpus) (Folder 6-15)
      - (Group I, File 320)
        - Artillery
          - General (Folder 16-21)
            Available on microfilm reel 147
          - Markovskii Artilleriiskii Divizion (Folder 22-26)
      - (Group I, File 321)
        - Commendation and Promotion Lists (Nagradnye Listy)
          - General (Box 122, Folder 1)
          - Kavkazskii Strelkovyi Polk (Folder 2-5)
          - Samurskii Pekhotnyi Polk (Folder 6)
            Available on microfilm reel 148
      - (Group I, File 322)
        - I-ia Artilleriiskaia Brigada (Folder 7-9)
        - Markovskii Pekhotnyi Polk (Folder 10-14)
      - (Group I, File 323)
        - Commendation and Promotion Lists (Nagradnye Listy) I-ia Pekhotnaia Diviziia, Drozdovskii Polk and Kavkazskii Strelkovy Polk, includes some Samurskii Strelkovyi Polk (Folder 15-20)
      - (Group I, File 323)
        - Commendation and promotion lists, contd. (Box 123, Folder 1-3)
          Available on microfilm reel 149
      - (Group I, File 324)
        - Military Service Records (Posluzhnye Spiski) and Commendation and Promotion Lists (Nagradnye Listy), Drozdovskii Strelkovyi Polk. Includes miscellaneous other units (Folder 4-12)
          Folders 4-11 available on microfilm reel 149; folder 12 on reel 150
      - (Group I, File 325)
        - Russkii Kadetskii Korpus, Markovskii Pekhotnyi Polk, Alekseevskii Pekhotnyi Polk, Nikolaevsko-Alekseevskii Inzhenernoe Uchilishche and other miscellaneous units (Folder 13-20)
          Available on microfilm reel 150
      - (Group I, File 325)
        - Russkii Kadetskii Korpus et al., contd. (Box 124, Folder 1-2)
        - Martynov, Maj.-Gen. Z., Commander Otriad Russkoi Armii v Gallipoli (Folder 3)
        - Vitkovskii, Maj.-Gen. V., Commander, Ofitserskago Generala Drozdovskago Divizii, 1919 (Folder 4)
          Available on microfilm reel 151
      - (Group I, File 326)
        - Alekseevskii Pekhotnyi Polk and miscellaneous other units (Folder 5)
        - Drozdovskii Strelkovyi Polk
          - General (Folder 6-14)
          - Konnyi Divizion (Folder 15)
      - (Group I, File 327)
        - Samurskii Pekhotnyi Polk and miscellaneous other units (Folder 16-19)
        - Alekseevskii Pekhotnyi Polk (Folder 20-21)
          Available on microfilm reel 152
        - Drozdovskii Strelkovyi Polk (Folder 22)
      - (Group I, File 327), contd.
        - Markovskii Pekhotnyi Polk (Box 125, Folder 1)
        - Kornilovskii Udarnyi Polk (Folder 2)
        - Svodnyi Gvardeiskii Polk (Folder 3-4)
      - (Group I, File 328)
        - Kornilovskii Udarnyi Polk, Drozdovskii Strelkovyi Polk and miscellaneous other units (Folder 5-7)
        - Artillery: miscellaneous units, including Drozdovskii and Alekseevskii Polk (Folder 8-9)
        - Russkii Kadetskii Korpus v Korolevstve S.KH.S. (Folder 10-11)
        - Administrative and medical personnel (Folder 12-14)
          Available on microfilm reel 153
      - (Group I, File 329)
        - Miscellaneous units (Folder 15-19)
      - (Group I, File 329)
        - Miscellaneous units, contd. (Box 126, Folder 1-7)
      - (Group I, File 330)
        - 1-yi, 2-oi and 4-yi Kavaleriiskii Polk. Includes miscellaneous other units (Folder 8-13)
          Available on microfilm reel 154
      - (Group I, File 331)
        - Sevastopol'skii Batal'ion (Folder 14-19)
      - (Group I, File 332)
        - Kavaleriiskaia Diviziia, includes miscellaneous cavalry units (Box 127, Folder 1-7)
          Available on microfilm reel 155
      - (Group I, File 333)
        - Kavaleriiskaia Diviziia, including Gvardeiskii Kavkazskii Polk and miscellaneous other units (Folder 8-19)
          Folders 8-14 available on microfilm reel 155; folders 15-19 on reel 156
      - (Group I, File 334)
        - Artillery, miscellaneous units (Box 128, Folder 1-9)
          Folders 1-5 available on microfilm reel 156; folders 6-9 on reel 157
      - (Group I, File 335)
        - Markovskii Pekhotnyi Polk, I-yi Kavaleriiskii Polk and miscellaneous other cavalry units (Folder 10-18)
          Folders 10-15 available on microfilm reel 157; folders 16-18 on reel 158
      - (Group I, File 336)
        - Artillery: I-ia Artilleriiskaia Brigada, Drozdovskaia Artilleriiskaia Brigada and miscellaneous other units (Box 129, Folder 1-8)
          Available on microfilm reel 158
      - (Group I, File 337)
        - Svodno-Strelkovyi Generala Drozdovskago Polk, I-iy Kornilovskii Udarnyi Polk and miscellaneous artillery units (Folder 9-15)
          Folder 9 available on microfilm reel 158; folders 10-15 on reel 159
      - (Group I, File 338)
        - I-yi Kavaleriiskii Polk, I-yi Kornilovskii Udarnyi Polk, Kubanskii Udarnyi Polk, Otdel'naia Inzhenernaia Rota Kornilovskoi Udarnoi Divizii and miscellaneous other units (Folder 16-19)
          Available on microfilm reel 159
      - (Group I, File 338)
        - I-yi Kavaleriiskii Polk etc., contd. (Box 130, Folder 1-6)
          Available on microfilm reel 160
      - (Group I, File 339)
        - Drozdovskaia Artilleriiskaia Brigada and miscellaneous other artillery units (Folder 7-15)
      - (Group I, File 340)
        - Ofitserskaia Artilleriiskaia SHkola, Kornilovskii Artilleriiskii Divizion, I-ia Artilleriiskaia Brigada and miscellaneous other artillery units (Folder 16-20)
          Available on microfilm reel 161
      - (Group I, File 340)
        - Ofiterskaia Artilleriiskaia SHkola etc., contd. (Box 131, Folder 1-4)
      - (Group I, File 341)
        - I-ia Artilleriiskaia Brigada, Kornilovskii Artilleriiskii Divizion, Otdel'nyi Konnyi Generala Alekseeva Divizion and miscellaneous other units (Folder 5-10)
          Folders 5-6 available on microfilm reel 161; folders 7-10 on reel 162
      - (Group I, File 342)
        - Gvardeiskii Kavalergardskii Polk, Artilleriiskaia Generala Markova Brigada, Strelkovyi Generala Drozdovskago Polk, I-yi Gvardeiskii Svodno-Kirasirskii Polk, Kornilovskii Udarnyi Polk and miscellaneous other units (Folder 11-20)
          Available on microfilm reel 162
      - (Group I, File 343)
        - Ofitserskaia Inzhenernaia SHkola, Alekseevskoe Voennoe Uchilishche and other military schools; technical section, including aviation, armored vehicle personnel, radio-telegraph section and corps of military engineers (Box 132, Folder 1-6)
          Available on microfilm reel 163
      - (Group I, File 344)
        - Artillery: Markovskii Artilleriiskii Divizion, Alekseevskii Artilleriiskii Divizion and miscellaneous technical personnel (Folder 7-12)
      - (Group I, File 345)
        - Konstantinovskoe Voennoe Uchilishche, Svodnyi Gvardeiskii Polk, Alekseevskii Pekhotnyi Polk, Drozdovskii Strelkovyi Polk and miscellaneous other units (Folder 13-19)
          Available on microfilm reel 164
      - (Group I, File 346)
        - Artillery: Kornilovskaia Artilleriiskaia Divizion, Markovskaia Artilleriiskaia Divizion, Drozdovskaia Artilleriiskaia Brigada (Box 133, Folder 1-9)
          Folders 1-3 available on microfilm reel 164; folders 4-9 on reel 165
      - (Group I, File 347)
        - Alekseevskii Pekhotnyi Polk (Folder 10-17)
          Available on microfilm reel 165
      - (Group I, File 348)
        - Tekhnicheskii Polk (Folder 18-20)
          Available on microfilm reel 166
      - (Group I, File 348)
        - Tekhnicheskii Polk, contd. (Box 134, Folder 1-5)
      - (Group I, File 349)
        - Artillery: Alekseevskii Artilleriiskii Divizion, Kornilovskaia Artilleriiskaia Brigada, Drozdovskaia Artilleriiskaia Brigada, I-ia Artilleriiskaia Brigada and miscellaneous other artillery units (Folder 6-12)
          Folders 6-7 available on microfilm reel 166; folders 7-12 on reel 167
      - (Group I, File 350)
        - Kornilovskoe Voennoe Uchilishche, technical section: miscellaneous units, Upravlenie Komendanta g. Gallipoli, miscellaneous Cossack units (Folder 13-19)
          Available on microfilm reel 167
      - (Group I, File 351)
        - Leib-Gvardii Kazachii Divizion, miscellaneous cavalry and technical units (Box 135, Folder 1-8)
          Folders 1-5 available on microfilm reel 168; folders 6-8 on reel 169
      - (Group I, File 352)
        - Miscellaneous units, mostly cavalry but some aviation and artillery (Folder 9-15)
          Available on microfilm reel 169
  - (Group I, File 353)
    - Perenesenie Prakha Generala Vrangelia v Belgrad, Izdanie Komiteta po uvekovecheniiu pamiati Glavnokomanduiushchago Russkoi Armiei generala barona P.N. Vrangelia, printed copy, October 1929 (Box 135, Folder 16)
    - 6 Oktiabria 1929 goda v g. Belgrade, printed copy (Folder 17)
- Part II: Bound volumes (Boxes 136-161)
  "Perechen' del arkhiva Glavnokomanduiushchago Russkoi armiei generala barona P.N. Vrangelia, otpravlennykh 4 aprelia 1929 na khranenie v Hoover War Library," typescript.
  Administrative matters related to Baron P. Vrangel's Government of the Crimea, the evacuation and maintainance of the Russian Army and political matters related to the Russian Army abroad. Includes: minutes of meetings, Osoboe Soveshchanie pri Glavnokomanduiushchem Dobrovol'cheskoi Armii, Osoboe Soveshchanie pri Glavnokomanduiushchem Vooruzhennymi Silami na IUge Rossii and other government bodies, including Soveshchanie...Senatora G.V. Glinki dlia obsuzhdeniia zemel'nago voprosa; diplomatic and other correspondence: Pravitel'stvo IUga Rossii; evacuation, housing and feeding of Russian Army and civilian refugees, including correspondence with French and British authorities; resettlement of military and civilian refugees; Russkii Sovet, miscellaneous material including minutes of meetings; Bulgarian crisis of 1922, miscellaneous material; monarchist organizations: printed matter and correspondence, including Baron P. Vrangel' and Grand Duke Kirill Vladimirovich; Grand Duke Nikolai Nikolaevich, the Russian National Movement, the Russian Army and Baron P. Vrangel' Administration and financial support of Russian army; activity of Gen.-of-Infantry A. Kutepov; printed matter, especially military newspapers; photographs of military units during first years of emigration, 1918-1925. Files 1-135.
  - Osoboe Soveshchanie pri Glavnokomanduiushchem Dobrovol' chskoi Armiei, minutes of meetings (zhurnal) No. typescript, September 28-December 21, 1918, 1-22 (Box 136, File File 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 170
  - Osoboe Soveshchanie pri Glavnokomanduiushchem Vooruzhennymi Silami na IUge Rossii, minutes of meetings (zhurnal), No. typescript, December 29, 1918-February 22, 1919, 23-38
  - Osoboe Soveshchanie pri Glavnokomanduiushchem Vooruzhennymi Silami na IUge Rossii, minutes of meetings (zhurnal), printed copies, February 26-November 8, 1919 (File File 2)
    Available on microfilm reel 171
  - Prikazy Pravitelia IUga Rossii i Glavnokomanduiushchago Russkoi Armiei, Typescript with holograph signatures and handwritten annotations, April 8-October 11, 1920 (File File 3)
    Available on microfilm reel 172
  - Minutes of meetings (zhurnaly), typescript (Box 137, File File 4)
    Available on microfilm reel 173
    - Sovet pri Glavnokomanduiushchem Vooruzhennymi Silami IUga Rossii, No., 1-35, April 9-August 3, 1920
    - Pravitel'stvo IUga Rossii, No. 10-October 22, 1920, 36-54, August
    - Komitet Snabzheniia Russkoi Armii, No., 1-5, August 9-October 15, 1920
    - Komissiia Snabzheniia Russkoi Armii, No. 1920, 1-6, August 26-October 13
  - Pravitel'stvo IUga Rossii, diplomatic correspondence, mostly re recognition of Soviet Union by British, French and American governments and negotiations with Poland re united anti-Bolshevik military action, includes correspondence and transcripts of telegrams: Baron P. Vrangel'; Morskoi Predstavitel' Glavnokomanduiushchago V.S.IU.R. pri Soiuznom Komandovanii v Konstantinopole, Capt. O. SHcherbachev; British High Commissioner, Constantinople, Admiral J. de Robeck; British Military Mission, Sebastopol, Gen. Percy; Predsedatel' Soveta Nachal'nikov Upravlenii, A. Krivoshein; Ministr Innostrannykh Del, P. Struve; French Military Mission, Sebastopol, Gen. Mangin; Russian Ambassador in Paris, V. Maklakov; Nachal'nik Upravleniia Inostrannykh Del, G. Trubetskoi; Russian Representative in Constantinople, A. Neratov; Poverennyi v Delakh v Londone, E. Sablin; Rear-Admiral G. Hope; Russian Ambassador in Tokyo; Nachal'nik IAponskoi Voennoi Missii pri Stavke, Maj. Takahasi; Sovetnik Posol'stva v Parizhe, N. de Basili; Président du Conseil, Ministre des Affaires Etrangères, Millerand; Ambassador to Washington, G. Bakhmetev; Comité Militaire Allié de Versailles, Maréchal Foch; Contre-Admiral Dumesnil; Senior Russian Diplomatic Representative Abroad, M. Girs; M. Paléologue; Lieut.-Gen. A. Lukomskii; S. Sazonov; A. Tyrkova-Williams. Typescript and holograph, March 9-November 4, 1920 (File File 5)
    Available on microfilm reel 174
  - Soveshchanie obrazovanoe pod predsedatel'stvom Senatora G.V. Glinki dlia obsuzhdeniia zemel'nago voprosa po prikazaniiu Glavnokomanduiushchago V.S.IU.R... Includes: minutes of meetings (zhurnal); dissenting opinions of committee members; drafts of resolutions and projects; newspaper clippings ( Tavricheskii Golos, IUzhnyia Vedomosti, Vechernii Kurier); "Prikaz Glavnokomanduiushchago Vooruzhennymi Silami na IUge Rossii o Zemle ot 25 maia goda," printed copy; report, "Svedeniia ob osushchestvlenii zemel'nago zakona Generala Vrangelia 25 maia 1920 goda k 15-mu oktiabria," typescript and handwritten (File File 6)
  - Russian property evacuated by Pravitel'stvo IUga Rossii to Constantinople and delivered into the safekeeping of the French government, November 27, 1920-April 6, 1921 (File File 8)
    - Correspondence: Baron P. Vrangel' to Comte de Martel, Haut Commissaire de France and Admiral Dumesnil; A. Neratov to Haut-Commissaire de France à Constantinople, A. Defrance; A. Defrance and A. Neratov; P. Struve to Ministre des Affaires Etrangères, G. Leygues; Président du Conseil, Commission de Liquidation Russe, Clairebont to P. Struve. Includes transcripts of telegrams between A. Neratov, E. Sablin, V. Maklakov and Lieut.-Gen. P. SHatilov, typescript; excerpt, "Liquidation du Compte Wrangel," Le Temps,; official lists of supplies and equipment under dispute, includes: "Vedomost' imushchestvu sostoiashchemu na uchete v nastoiashchee vremia s ukazaniem primerno stoimosti vo frankakh"; "Vedomost' khlebnym produktam v zerne i pererabotannym pribyvshim iz Kryma 9 Ianvaria, 1921"; "Spisok transportov Morskogo Vedomstva"; "Spisok katrov i buksirov M.V."; "Vedomost' predmetam artilleriiskago imushchestva vziatago frantsuzami u Russkoi Armii"; "Vedomost' intendantskomu imushchestvu..."; "Barzhi, podchalki i pontony rechnoi transportnoi flotilii," typescript and handwritten, December 13, 1920
  - Evacuation, housing and feeding of Russian Army and civilian refugees, mostly at Gallipoli and Lemnos; negotiations with Allies re future of Russian Army and civilian refugees including resettlement in Europe or South America and repatriation to Soviet Union; conflicts between Russian Army and French military authorities, typescript, November 1920-April 1921 (Box 138, File File 9)
    Available on microfilm reel 175
    - Correspondence: Baron P. Vrangel', including appeals to international community and orders to Russian Army; Chief of Staff, G.H.Q., Russian Army, Lieut.-Gen. P. SHatilov; Chef du Service de Santé et de Secours aux Réfugies Russes, S. Il'ine... Russian Mission in Greece, P. Demidov; Comité de Secours russe de l'Union des membres des Villes et Zemstvos à l'étranger, Prince L'vov; Russkii Parlamentskii Komitet v Konstantinopole, I. Aleksinskii; Rossiiskoe Obshchestvo Krasnago Kresta; Corps d'Occupation de Constantinople, Etat-Major, Gen. Nayral de Bourgon; Escadre de Mediterranée Orientale, Vice-Admiral De Bon; A. Defrance... Commandant le Corps d'Occupation de Constantinople, Gen. C. Charpy; Ministère des Affaires Etrangères, Aristide Briand; Haut Commissariat de la République Française, Service Politique, Gen. Pelle; American Red Cross; transcripts of telegrams between P. Struve, A. Neratov, V. Maklakov, M. Girs, also A. Guchkov to H. Hoover, President W. Harding, and Secretary of State Hughes; recruitment of Russian military personnel into French Foreign Legion; transport of military and civilian refugees from Hademkeuy-Tchataldja camps to Gallipoli and Lemnos; reports re composition, condition, feeding and housing of troops and civilian refugees on Gallipoli and Lemnos, including correspondence and orders of Le Commandant d'Armes, Ile de Lemnos, Gen. Broussaud, Komandir Kubanskogo Korpusa Gen. M. Fostikov and Komandir Donskogo Korpusa, Lieut.-Gen. F. Abramov; Russian Naval Squadron in Bizerte; repatriation of Cossacks to Soviet Union, specifically aboard French vessel "Reshid-Pasha"; French project for settlement of refugees in France, Brazil, Peru and Madagascar; report re "Selimie" Camp
  - Maintainance of Russian Army and civilian refugees, mostly problem of resettlement and repatriation including negotiations between Russian government in exile, French government and governments of Bulgaria, Czechoslovakia and Serbia. Deals most specifically with situation in refugee camp on Island of Lemnos, typescript and handwritten, April 2-May 25, 1921 (File File 10)
    Available on microfilm reel 176